lafraise.com 2014-11-21

# Privacy Policy | laFraise Blog EN

## Privacy Policy of laFraise Ltd.

### Principal

The safety and privacy of personal data has a special value for laFraise Ltd. (hereinafter laFraise). The collection, processing and usage of personal data shall only be undertaken with the consent of the individual or due to a legal obligation. Should anonymous or pseudonymous data be needed for business purposes, then only these forms of data shall be used. Personal data stored at laFraise is protected by extensive technical and operational safeguards against potential unauthorised access or abuse. Our security procedures are regularly reviewed along with the latest technological developments. laFraise uses a secure method of data transmission known as SSL (Secure Socket Layer) transmission to process user information.

### laFraise Orders and Membership

We collect; store; modify; use and transmit personal data for their own specific purposes towards the justification and settlement of the user’s contract or contract relationships, including individual and personal customer advice and support, and to protect the legitimate business interests of laFraise. When necessary, we will transmit personal data to third parties (such as delivery companies). Only information that is needed to carry out its task will be transmitted and used. The usage and transmission of personal data for advertising and market-research purposes is permitted by laFraise, unless the user asks us to withhold their personal information when setting up their contract with us. Users can opt-out of the usage of their data at any time within their laFraise user-account or by sending a request via email to service@laFraise.com The usage of personal data for other appropriate purposes is dependent on prior consent from the user.

### Usage of laFraise’s Online Offers

laFraise collects and uses personal user data due to legal obligations or when permission from a user is given, for the reason of content-wise alterations or changes to the contractual relations with the user in terms of the usage of tele-media. As far as is necessary, laFraise collects and uses a personal data in order to enable users to operate their online service; for accounting; further legally permissible cases or with the users consent. laFraise collects and uses data contained in log-files that the user’s internet browser transmits to us. The data we receive is the user’s browser type/version; operating system; referring URLs (the user’s previously visited site); hostname (IP address) of the accessing computer and the time of server inquiry. In order to ensure the safe communication of the laFraise online service – it is not necessary for laFraise to use the data collected in connection with the specific user. Therefore, after statistical evaluation the data will be deleted and not used in connection with the user.

### Usage of Cookies

For the reason of improving laFraise’s online service, the commonly-named system of ‘Cookies’ are used. Cookies are text files, which are stored on a users computer when they visit a website. Cookies are used either once or over a longer period of time to use a user’s recurring attitudes within the laFraise site to their benefit – in terms of personalising the laFraise online experience and its functions and tools towards individual user’s needs. The text files contain no address data (i.e. user’s names and E-Mail data) or other personal information. laFraise will not link data found in these text files with other data sources. Cookies serve to further our analysis of web-page usage and enables us to make our service more user-friendly; more effective and safer. In terms of the data collected within its online service, laFraise works together with Omniture, Inc., 550 East Timpanogos Circle, Orem, Utah 84097 (Omniture). Omniture use cookies and web-beacons (small graphics implanted into websites that make log-file recording and analysis possible). The acquisition and processing of data is purely for statistical purposes and serve for the improvement of laFraise’s online service. Only data that is not linked to the original user is collected and used. User profiles (using false pseudonyms) may be provided for the purpose of advertisement to marketing-studies or for organising the meeting of demand within our online service, should the user not object. Users can opt-out of their information being used at any time by deactivating this function within their laFraise user account, or by requesting deactivation via email (service@laFraise.com). The user-profile will in no circumstances, be linked with the data regarding the ‘pseudonym’.

### Deactivation of Cookies

Users can set their web browser to halt the storage of the data files known as Cookies. In some cases this can lead to certain services and website functions to become unusable.

### Email advertising with newsletter subscriptions and postal advertising

If you have signed up to receiving the newsletter, we will send you our promotional emails to your address as long as you don’t deregister. And if you have agreed to receive advertising via email, we will use your address data for the use of our promotions as long as you don’t deregister. You can always opt out, and it doesn’t incur any costs other than what you pay your Internet provider for using its services.

### Email advertising without newsletter registration

You initially registered with your email address. In case you haven’t opted out of receiving information on products similar to those in your first registration by un-ticking the respective box, we will keep sending you product information. This means that we are using your email address for the purpose of our product advertising alone.

### Right of objection to data usage for advertising

You can of course always object to further usage of your data for promotional purposes, even to those purposes that legally don’t require your consent. You can do so by sending us a simple message, and it doesn’t incur any costs other than what you pay your Internet provider for using its services.  
Please use one of the following communication channels to get in touch with us:

  * via E-Mail to service@lafraise.com,
  * in the newsletter administration of your laFraise user account,
  * through the un-follow link of the laFraise newsletter,
  * via phone to +44 203 137 2837
  * via fax to +49 341 594 00 5149 or
  * post directed to laFraise Ltd., Acorn Business Campus, Mahon Industrial Park, Blackrock, Cork, Republic of Ireland

### User Rights to Access to Personal Information

Visitors and users of laFraise’s web page can request (free of charge) access to any information held about them and its origin; any recipients of their data and the reason for the storage of such data.
